[
    {
        "question": "1. What is SSIS?",
        "answer": "SSIS stands for SQL Server Integration Services. It is a part of the Microsoft SQL server and is a well-known integrated platform for performing enterprise-level data migration and transformation activities. The platform is used for solving complex problems like reading, loading, copying, or downloading large files, mining data, extracting relevant information, and managing SQL objects. It supports data sources like relational databases, XML, flat files, etc, and helps to load and send data to multiple destinations. SQL Server Integration Services",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is an SSIS task?",
        "answer": "Tasks are units of work and are present in SSIS packages. We have different task types depending on the type of work that needs to be performed. Below are some of the most commonly used tasks present in SSIS: Execute SQLTask: Used for executing SQL statements in relational databases.\nData Flow Task: Used for reading data from one or more data sources, transforming them, and loading it to various destinations as required.\nAnalysis Services Processing Task: Used for processing objects of the tabular model or SSAS (SQL Server Analysis Services) cubes.\nFTP Tasks: Used for sending and receiving files from FTP Servers to our local folders.\nScript Task: Used for writing .Net code as per requirements.\nSend Mail Task: Used for sending emails for notifying users regarding status, progress, or outcomes of tasks.\nExecute Package Task: Used for calling different packages of the same project. It also has the feature of passing the value of variables to the package.\nExecute Process Task: Used for running application as a whole or as a batch script. It can also be used for opening software like Microsoft Word, Excel, etc, and for unzipping compressed files.\nFile System Task: Used for performing file system manipulations like move files, rename them, delete them, change the location, etc.\nCustom Task: If all the existing tasks do not meet our requirements, then SSIS provides flexibility to create new custom tasks. Execute SQLTask: Used for executing SQL statements in relational databases. Execute SQLTask: Data Flow Task: Used for reading data from one or more data sources, transforming them, and loading it to various destinations as required. Data Flow Task: Analysis Services Processing Task: Used for processing objects of the tabular model or SSAS (SQL Server Analysis Services) cubes. Analysis Services Processing Task: FTP Tasks: Used for sending and receiving files from FTP Servers to our local folders. FTP Tasks: Script Task: Used for writing .Net code as per requirements. Script Task: Send Mail Task: Used for sending emails for notifying users regarding status, progress, or outcomes of tasks. Send Mail Task: Execute Package Task: Used for calling different packages of the same project. It also has the feature of passing the value of variables to the package. Execute Package Task: Execute Process Task: Used for running application as a whole or as a batch script. It can also be used for opening software like Microsoft Word, Excel, etc, and for unzipping compressed files. Execute Process Task: File System Task: Used for performing file system manipulations like move files, rename them, delete them, change the location, etc. File System Task: Custom Task: If all the existing tasks do not meet our requirements, then SSIS provides flexibility to create new custom tasks. Custom Task:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What are packages in SSIS?",
        "answer": "SSIS packages are organized collections of various connections and elements related to data flow, event handlers, variables, control flow, configurations, or parameters that would be used for assembling and programmatically building graphical design tools. They can also be used for populating data from different sources which can be later used for standardizing and administrative purposes. They are created in BIDS - Business Intelligent Development Studio.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What do you understand by SSIS expressions?",
        "answer": "SSIS Expressions are used for filtering information based on parameters and conditions to get desired information. They make lives easy by helping to work with conditions, loops, and dynamic connections. The expression could consist of symbols, literals, identifiers, operators, and functions. They are mainly used for updating properties dynamically at runtime. Once we have the expressions ready, an expression evaluator parses this expression for validating the rules of the expression.\nThe expressions are used for the below 2 cases:  Control Flow:\nHere, the variable values are derived using other variables employing expressions.\nFor validating any condition, precedence constraints are used.\nUsed for setting properties dynamically at runtime by tasks and containers.\nData Flow:\nExpressions are used on rows to get conditional split transformations evaluating to true or false.\nHelps to create a new column based on the result of applying expressions to get derived transformations on new columns. Control Flow:\nHere, the variable values are derived using other variables employing expressions.\nFor validating any condition, precedence constraints are used.\nUsed for setting properties dynamically at runtime by tasks and containers. Control Flow: Here, the variable values are derived using other variables employing expressions.\nFor validating any condition, precedence constraints are used.\nUsed for setting properties dynamically at runtime by tasks and containers. Here, the variable values are derived using other variables employing expressions. For validating any condition, precedence constraints are used. Used for setting properties dynamically at runtime by tasks and containers. Data Flow:\nExpressions are used on rows to get conditional split transformations evaluating to true or false.\nHelps to create a new column based on the result of applying expressions to get derived transformations on new columns. Data Flow: Expressions are used on rows to get conditional split transformations evaluating to true or false.\nHelps to create a new column based on the result of applying expressions to get derived transformations on new columns. Expressions are used on rows to get conditional split transformations evaluating to true or false. Helps to create a new column based on the result of applying expressions to get derived transformations on new columns.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Define Manifest file.",
        "answer": "The manifest file is the utility having information that is useful for deploying packages using file system wizard and database of SQL server.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Differentiate between SSIS and Informatica.",
        "answer": "Feature SSIS Informatica\nSecurity Secure Secure\nMaintenance and Administration Easy Difficult\nEase of Implementation Easy Moderate\nPerformance in a medium SQL server environment Performs well Performs well\nProductivity Moderate High in large applications implementation\nAuto Documentation Not available Available\nCost No cost Expensive\nProduct Maturity Younger Was present much before to SSIS Feature SSIS Informatica\nSecurity Secure Secure\nMaintenance and Administration Easy Difficult\nEase of Implementation Easy Moderate\nPerformance in a medium SQL server environment Performs well Performs well\nProductivity Moderate High in large applications implementation\nAuto Documentation Not available Available\nCost No cost Expensive\nProduct Maturity Younger Was present much before to SSIS Feature SSIS Informatica Feature SSIS Informatica Feature SSIS Informatica Security Secure Secure\nMaintenance and Administration Easy Difficult\nEase of Implementation Easy Moderate\nPerformance in a medium SQL server environment Performs well Performs well\nProductivity Moderate High in large applications implementation\nAuto Documentation Not available Available\nCost No cost Expensive\nProduct Maturity Younger Was present much before to SSIS Security Secure Secure Security Secure Secure Maintenance and Administration Easy Difficult Maintenance and Administration Easy Difficult Ease of Implementation Easy Moderate Ease of Implementation Easy Moderate Performance in a medium SQL server environment Performs well Performs well Performance in a medium SQL server environment Performs well Performs well Productivity Moderate High in large applications implementation Productivity Moderate High in large applications implementation Auto Documentation Not available Available Auto Documentation Not available Available Cost No cost Expensive Cost No cost Expensive Product Maturity Younger Was present much before to SSIS Product Maturity Younger Was present much before to SSIS",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is data transformation in SSIS?",
        "answer": "Data transformation is the process of extracting required data from a data source and is the most critical SSIS step. Post extraction, the process aids in managing and transferring the data to a specific file destination. There are several rules implemented by this process for loading the extracted data to the destination target file. Based on this, the transformations are classified as:  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Define SSIS Catalog. Is it possible to deploy user-defined packages in the catalog?",
        "answer": "SSIS catalog is the database where all deployed packages are stored securely. This helps to control and handle the deployed packages effectively. The users can deploy their packages too. All the deployed packages are stored in the catalog as a centralized database.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What is SSIS Container?",
        "answer": "SSIS containers are defined as a set of logically linked tasks that allows the management of the task scope effectively. Containers allow looping through tasks set until tasks are grouped logically or until specified criteria are met. Nesting of containers is also allowed and the containers are set in the Package designer section in the Control flow tab.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. In SSIS, what are the variable types that can be created?",
        "answer": "SSIS permits the creation of two variable types- global and task-specific variables. The scope of global variables is available for all tasks of a specified process. The task-specific variables have scope specific to the task. global task-specific",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Define SSIS Checkpoint.",
        "answer": "SSIS checkpoint is a property that provides a point of restart from the failure point. When the checkpoint property is set to true, a checkpoint file is created which consists of all the relevant information required to run the package from the point of failure. If the package is run successfully, the file is deleted and is recreated again when the package runs. This is particularly useful as it avoids re-running the whole project when the execution fails.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. Define Precedence Constraint.",
        "answer": "Precedence Constraint is used for enabling the developers to define a set of tasks logically and define the order of execution. These are connectors used for connecting all the tasks.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What are SSIS Connection Managers?",
        "answer": "Connection Managers are used for gathering data from various sources and sending it to a destination. It facilitates system connection by including information regarding server, data source, authentication details, database, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. How are SSIS Packages more advantageous than stored procedures?",
        "answer": "SSIS has more advantages when dealing with complex transformation processes involving slow-changing dimensions. They are: SSIS is known for managing memory efficiently thereby resulting in much bigger improvements in performance when compared to stored procedures.\nSSIS supports GUI (Graphical User Interface) and helps developers develop complex transformations easily and in a reliable way.]\nSSIS helps in easier interaction with external sources which are particularly useful during data cleansing. SSIS is known for managing memory efficiently thereby resulting in much bigger improvements in performance when compared to stored procedures. SSIS supports GUI (Graphical User Interface) and helps developers develop complex transformations easily and in a reliable way.] SSIS helps in easier interaction with external sources which are particularly useful during data cleansing. If the ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) process consists majorly of Extract and Load with very little Transform, then Stored Procedures work well because they do not deal with cursors.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Define conditional split transformations.",
        "answer": "These are the transformations that are similar to the IF-ELSE condition of programming languages which checks for the condition and executes the process if the condition evaluates to true. Here, we can also specify the order of evaluation for the conditions and also provide the default value as the output.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. What are Process Bytes in SSIS?",
        "answer": "Process bytes represent the amount of memory currently used by the Integration services. This memory cannot be shared by other processes.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What are the disadvantages of SSIS?",
        "answer": "There are some disadvantages while using SSIS. They are as follows: If we need to see the report of package execution, then we will have to install new software called Management Studio. SSIS does not have the option to publish to reporting services.\nSSIS utilizes high memory which can cause conflicts with memory utilization of SQL. This causes problems if there are requirements to run multiple packages in parallel.\nSSIS also uses high CPU resources which again results in problems while running multiple packages parallely. Proper CPU allocation needs to be ensured between SQL and SSIS to avoid either of them running slow. If we need to see the report of package execution, then we will have to install new software called Management Studio. SSIS does not have the option to publish to reporting services. SSIS utilizes high memory which can cause conflicts with memory utilization of SQL. This causes problems if there are requirements to run multiple packages in parallel. SSIS also uses high CPU resources which again results in problems while running multiple packages parallely. Proper CPU allocation needs to be ensured between SQL and SSIS to avoid either of them running slow.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. How is error handling done in SSIS?",
        "answer": "During the process of transferring millions of records from one source to a destination, the probability of errors always exists. It is very important to identify the records that are errored out and ensure the transmission of records is smooth with no errors to the destination. To identify the errors, the errors need to be logged. The components of SSIS - source, transformation, and the destination - all have had support to log errors to output by means of secondary pipe by providing means to define behaviors while errors occur.   The secondary pipe or the error flow can be connected to another transformation or a destination component depending on the requirement. The error log can contain details regarding the error columns, error descriptions, and error codes.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. Is it possible to log SSIS execution?",
        "answer": "Yes. SSIS supports logging which helps the system in analyzing and writing log entries during any run-time events. It also supports logging of custom messages, which the developer has to manually enable. Since the SSIS deals with a variety of data sources, logging is supported in multiple formats such as logging information to text files, XML files, Windows Log, etc. The scope of the logs is packages. They are maintained at the package level which means that any task that runs from the package can log information to other package logs.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What will you do if a package runs fine in BIDS but fails while running from the SQL agent job?",
        "answer": "A package that runs successfully in BIDS and fails from the SQL agent job can mean that the SQL Agent jobs do not have the necessary permission for some connections of the package. We can either create a proxy account that allows SQL Agent jobs to run the package or elevate the current account permissions. Conclusion: SSIS is a platform for integration services that provide automated tasks and various transformation components for cleaning, transforming, and validating data throughout the process of data loading from source to destination. In this article, we have seen what are the most commonly asked SSIS interview questions and the answers to them. Interview Resources: Database\nSQL Interview\nSQL Server Interview\nAzure Data Factory Database Database SQL Interview SQL Interview SQL Server Interview SQL Server Interview Azure Data Factory Azure Data Factory",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. How will you add a recordset variable inside Script Task?",
        "answer": "Variables are used in script tasks to facilitate data exchange with other objects of the package. Script task makes use of the property called Variables of Dts object for reading and writing to variable objects of the package. To make the variables available to the custom script, we need to add them to read-only or read-write variable lists. The variable names are case-sensitive and care has to be taken while adding the variables to the list. We can use the Value property for reading and writing data to the variables.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. How do you store SQL passwords? Does the SSIS connection manager of the package store SQL password?",
        "answer": "The SSIS connection manager has issues in storing the password. Hence we can follow the below-proposed solutions: Method 1: Create and use SQL Server Agent Proxy account which uses credential that makes SQL Server Agent capable of the running job as an account having required permissions to run the job or as the account which created the package.\nThis method is used for decrypting secrets and key requirements of the user are satisfied.\nThere are chances that this method could fail because the secrets are decrypted by taking the current user and current computer information which will inadvertently fail if the project or package is moved to a different computer.\nMethod 2: Set the value of Package Protection Level Property to Server Storage. This stores packages on the SQL Server and lets users access this through SQL Server database roles.\nMethod 3: Set the value of Package Protection Level property as “Encrypt Sensitive with Password”. The method uses a password for encrypting sensitive information. This can be added to the SQL Server Agent job to run the job effectively.\nMethod 4: Package configuration can be used to save sensitive information which can later be stored in a secured folder. When the package is run, the information is obtained from this config file. If we do not want to save the secrets in the package, we can set the property of Protection Level to “DontSaveSensitive”.\nMethod 5: Package templates having a good protection level can be created for long-term solutions. Method 1: Create and use SQL Server Agent Proxy account which uses credential that makes SQL Server Agent capable of the running job as an account having required permissions to run the job or as the account which created the package.\nThis method is used for decrypting secrets and key requirements of the user are satisfied.\nThere are chances that this method could fail because the secrets are decrypted by taking the current user and current computer information which will inadvertently fail if the project or package is moved to a different computer. Method 1 This method is used for decrypting secrets and key requirements of the user are satisfied.\nThere are chances that this method could fail because the secrets are decrypted by taking the current user and current computer information which will inadvertently fail if the project or package is moved to a different computer. This method is used for decrypting secrets and key requirements of the user are satisfied. There are chances that this method could fail because the secrets are decrypted by taking the current user and current computer information which will inadvertently fail if the project or package is moved to a different computer. Method 2: Set the value of Package Protection Level Property to Server Storage. This stores packages on the SQL Server and lets users access this through SQL Server database roles. Method 2 Method 3: Set the value of Package Protection Level property as “Encrypt Sensitive with Password”. The method uses a password for encrypting sensitive information. This can be added to the SQL Server Agent job to run the job effectively. Method 3 Method 4: Package configuration can be used to save sensitive information which can later be stored in a secured folder. When the package is run, the information is obtained from this config file. If we do not want to save the secrets in the package, we can set the property of Protection Level to “DontSaveSensitive”. Method 4 Method 5: Package templates having a good protection level can be created for long-term solutions. Method 5",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Explain the importance of config files in SSIS.",
        "answer": "The config file is used for providing inputs to the connection manager about the properties used by the packages and tasks at the run-time. This is especially useful when the changes are deployed on multiple locations or servers as we do not have to worry every time package runs about configuration. Depending on the server or location, the config files are automatically picked and used.\nWe can store config properties in multiple ways. Some of them are:  XML configuration file: Data can be stored as an XML file.\nEnvironment variables: The config data can be stores as part of environment variables.\nRegistry entry: The config can be stored in the registry.\nParent package variable: The config can be stored as a variable in a package of a task.\nSQL Server: The config can be stored in a database table on the SQL Server. XML configuration file: Data can be stored as an XML file. XML configuration file: Environment variables: The config data can be stores as part of environment variables. Environment variables: Registry entry: The config can be stored in the registry. Registry entry: Parent package variable: The config can be stored as a variable in a package of a task. Parent package variable: SQL Server: The config can be stored in a database table on the SQL Server. SQL Server:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What is SSIS event logging property?",
        "answer": "This property gives us the flexibility to log or not to log the events while running the components - tasks and packages - in SSIS.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What are the components that would be used to send data from the access database to the SQL database on the off chance?",
        "answer": "We will be using the following three components: One OLE DB Source\nInformation Conversion Change\nOne SQL Server Goal\nOLE DB source is used to get information from the Access database source. Information conversion change is used in case of any datatype anomaly due to data contrast between source and destination databases. SQL Server Goal is utilized when we have the bundle run from the same machine and our database server is put on at the off chance. It is used for improving the SQL goal. One OLE DB Source Information Conversion Change One SQL Server Goal\nOLE DB source is used to get information from the Access database source. Information conversion change is used in case of any datatype anomaly due to data contrast between source and destination databases. SQL Server Goal is utilized when we have the bundle run from the same machine and our database server is put on at the off chance. It is used for improving the SQL goal. ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is SSIS breakpoint?",
        "answer": "An SSIS breakpoint is a property that allows developers to debug and review the variable or data status at any point by pausing the execution of the package in the project. The breakpoints are configured in Business Intelligence Development Studio, generally known as BIDS. The following steps are followed to apply or remove SSIS breakpoints: Go to the control flow interface within the BIDS section.\nRight-click on the object that we want to apply or remove the breakpoint.\nSelect “Edit Breakpoint” and enable/disable the breakpoint. Go to the control flow interface within the BIDS section. Right-click on the object that we want to apply or remove the breakpoint. Select “Edit Breakpoint” and enable/disable the breakpoint.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Is it possible to schedule packages for a specific time period of a day?",
        "answer": "Yes. This can be done by designing SQL Server Agent Job with work steps similar to the SSIS package. This job fetches the dtexec order utility to execute the bundle. This created bundle can be run or requested based on the requirement or can be rescheduled based on the recurring requirement.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. How many lookup cache modes are present in SSIS?",
        "answer": "There are 3 types of lookup cache modes. These are part of Lookup Transformation in SSIS.   Full Cache Mode: This mode helps in querying the database before the data-flow task is executed. This constitutes a critical part of the pre-execution step of the data-flow task. In this mode, the entire data copy is copied from the table and stored into the lookup cache in SSIS.\nPartial Cache Mode: This mode helps in querying new rows in the database from different data sources. Here, the matched row data is cached into the SSIS lookup cache. If the lookup cache is full, the data is removed automatically from the cache based on the usage statistics of the existing rows to free up space for newly matched rows.\nNo Cache Mode: Here, the data is not cached unless 2 subsequent sources come up with the same matched rows. Database queries are run to get matched data every time from the source. Full Cache Mode: This mode helps in querying the database before the data-flow task is executed. This constitutes a critical part of the pre-execution step of the data-flow task. In this mode, the entire data copy is copied from the table and stored into the lookup cache in SSIS. Full Cache Mode Partial Cache Mode: This mode helps in querying new rows in the database from different data sources. Here, the matched row data is cached into the SSIS lookup cache. If the lookup cache is full, the data is removed automatically from the cache based on the usage statistics of the existing rows to free up space for newly matched rows. Partial Cache Mode No Cache Mode: Here, the data is not cached unless 2 subsequent sources come up with the same matched rows. Database queries are run to get matched data every time from the source. No Cache Mode",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What does the data profiling task do?",
        "answer": "Data profiling is the process of examining information by comprehending its condition, readability, examples, nulls, or numbers. This is performed at the beginning of the advancement cycle for structuring the database blueprint and assessing the quality of the data.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. Explain the types of SSIS containers.",
        "answer": "The following containers are present in SSIS: Task Host Containers: Default container where all single tasks are available and are used for background scenes in SSIS. This is not present in the toolbox of Visual Studio and is assigned to the task implicitly. This container is also used to extend event handlers and variables.\nSequence Containers: These handle the flow of package subset and helps to divide packages into smaller pieces.\nThese are displayed in the Control Flow tab. We can drag and drop containers from the toolbox in the design pane and then add a set of tasks into the container. Following things can be achieved using sequence containers:\nGroup tasks for disabling a portion of the unused package.\nTo narrow the variable scope to the container.\nManage properties of tasks easily by setting container properties.\nEnsure multiple executions of tasks by making use of one method.\nCreate transactions for data-related tasks and not package as a whole.\nCreate event handlers such as sending mail in case things go wrong.\nThe below example shows two tasks that need to be successfully executed before calling the third script task. Task Host Containers: Default container where all single tasks are available and are used for background scenes in SSIS. This is not present in the toolbox of Visual Studio and is assigned to the task implicitly. This container is also used to extend event handlers and variables. Task Host Containers: Sequence Containers: These handle the flow of package subset and helps to divide packages into smaller pieces.\nThese are displayed in the Control Flow tab. We can drag and drop containers from the toolbox in the design pane and then add a set of tasks into the container. Following things can be achieved using sequence containers:\nGroup tasks for disabling a portion of the unused package.\nTo narrow the variable scope to the container.\nManage properties of tasks easily by setting container properties.\nEnsure multiple executions of tasks by making use of one method.\nCreate transactions for data-related tasks and not package as a whole.\nCreate event handlers such as sending mail in case things go wrong.\nThe below example shows two tasks that need to be successfully executed before calling the third script task. Sequence Containers: These are displayed in the Control Flow tab. We can drag and drop containers from the toolbox in the design pane and then add a set of tasks into the container. Following things can be achieved using sequence containers:\nGroup tasks for disabling a portion of the unused package.\nTo narrow the variable scope to the container.\nManage properties of tasks easily by setting container properties.\nEnsure multiple executions of tasks by making use of one method.\nCreate transactions for data-related tasks and not package as a whole.\nCreate event handlers such as sending mail in case things go wrong.\nThe below example shows two tasks that need to be successfully executed before calling the third script task. These are displayed in the Control Flow tab. We can drag and drop containers from the toolbox in the design pane and then add a set of tasks into the container. Following things can be achieved using sequence containers:\nGroup tasks for disabling a portion of the unused package.\nTo narrow the variable scope to the container.\nManage properties of tasks easily by setting container properties.\nEnsure multiple executions of tasks by making use of one method.\nCreate transactions for data-related tasks and not package as a whole.\nCreate event handlers such as sending mail in case things go wrong. Group tasks for disabling a portion of the unused package.\nTo narrow the variable scope to the container.\nManage properties of tasks easily by setting container properties.\nEnsure multiple executions of tasks by making use of one method.\nCreate transactions for data-related tasks and not package as a whole.\nCreate event handlers such as sending mail in case things go wrong. Group tasks for disabling a portion of the unused package. To narrow the variable scope to the container. Manage properties of tasks easily by setting container properties. Ensure multiple executions of tasks by making use of one method.\nCreate transactions for data-related tasks and not package as a whole. Create transactions for data-related tasks and not package as a whole. Create transactions for data-related tasks and not package as a whole. Create event handlers such as sending mail in case things go wrong. The below example shows two tasks that need to be successfully executed before calling the third script task.   For Loop Containers: Helps to create a loop in the execution of packages. SSIS does this by initializing expression optionally and continues evaluation until expression becomes false. In the below example, We have the task name “Wait for file to arrive” which is inside For Loop Container, and the task is executed until the expression is evaluated to false. The Load File task is executed after the loop execution is complete. For Loop Containers: Helps to create a loop in the execution of packages. SSIS does this by initializing expression optionally and continues evaluation until expression becomes false. In the below example, We have the task name “Wait for file to arrive” which is inside For Loop Container, and the task is executed until the expression is evaluated to false. The Load File task is executed after the loop execution is complete. For Loop Containers:   Foreach Containers: This comprises of powerful loop mechanism which enables the loop using object collection. As the collection is looped, the variable is assigned values from the collection which is used by connections or tasks outside or within the container. Foreach Containers: This comprises of powerful loop mechanism which enables the loop using object collection. As the collection is looped, the variable is assigned values from the collection which is used by connections or tasks outside or within the container. Foreach Containers:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. Difference between Merge Transformation and Union all transformations.",
        "answer": "Merge Transformation: This does the task of merging data from 2 sources to single output. This is useful when we need to break the data flow path to a separate error path and once the error is handled, merge that back to the main data flow. To apply this transformation, the data should be sorted first and the metadata information for the 2 paths should be the same. The sorting can be done by applying sort transformation before the merge or by providing an ORDER BY clause in the source connection. Merge Transformation   Union All Transformation: Union all transformation working is similar to merge transformation but the only difference is that this does not require sorted data. Data from different sources are transformed and combined into a single output. Union All Transformation",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. Define Data Flow in SSIS.",
        "answer": "Data flow is the data transferring process from the source to a specified donation. It defines the way how data or information is sent from one point to other. It consists of 3 main components:   SSIS gives control to the users to perform the data transformation process from source to destination utilizing various built-in transformation components. The components provided by the SSIS helps users in data cleaning and manipulation in the pipeline. For achieving this, the user needs to attach a data flow task to the package control flow which is later executed within the package by creating, ordering, and running the data flow. It is worthy to note that each data flow task has a separate data flow engine instance.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. How is the deployment utility created in SSIS?",
        "answer": "Deployment is nothing but a process of updating the state of the package from development mode to executable mode. Deployment in SSIS can be done by simply performing the right-click operation on the “Integration Services Project” and clicking on the build option. This would create a “package.dtsx” file inside the bin folder named “projectbin”. The utility helps in deploying packages at SQL server or as an executable file on a specified location. build Following are the steps followed to create a deployment utility: Go to Project and right-click on it.\nDouble click on the properties.\nChoose the path location for deployment by selecting the box next to “True” under Create Deployment Utility.\nSave changes. Close this window.\nRight-click again on the project and select the build option. This creates a deployment folder in the project’s root within the BIN folder.\nThe deployment folder will have a .manifest file.\nDouble-clicking on the .manifest file and selecting the deploy option will perform package deployment on the SQL server. Go to Project and right-click on it. Double click on the properties. properties Choose the path location for deployment by selecting the box next to “True” under Create Deployment Utility. Save changes. Close this window. Right-click again on the project and select the build option. This creates a deployment folder in the project’s root within the BIN folder. build The deployment folder will have a .manifest file. Double-clicking on the .manifest file and selecting the deploy option will perform package deployment on the SQL server.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "1) What is SSIS?",
        "answer": "SSIS is a short form of 'SQL Server Integration Services'. It is one of the significant components of Microsoft SQL Server and was initially introduced with SQL Server 2005. SQL Server 2005 is said to be the next generation of SQL Server program after SQL Server 2000, and it replaced the DTS (Data Transformation Services) in SQL Server 2000.\nSSIS is very beneficial for accomplishing a wide variety of data transformation, data integration, and data migration jobs. SSIS is also known as an ETL tool mainly used to handle tasks related to data extraction, data transformation, and load operations. Additionally, SSIS also enables developers to use it for tasks other than ETL, such as data profiling, file system manipulation, etc. Apart from this, we can perform powerful batch operations in SSIS with the support of programming languages like C#.net or VB.net. In general, most companies use SSIS to store and manage their data in warehouses, and further extract and load it whenever required.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) What is meant by the SSIS package?",
        "answer": "An SSIS package is an organized set of connections such as control events, data flow elements, parameters, event handlers, variables and configurations. We can usually assemble a package in SSIS using the design tools or using programming and codes. Typically, SSIS packages are created in Business Intelligence Development Studio (also called BIDS in short).\nSSIS packages can merge data from heterogeneous data sources into the File System, SQL Server, or Package Store. These packages can also be used to clean and standardize data, populate data warehouses, and automate administrative tasks.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) What are the main components/parts of the SSIS package?",
        "answer": "The following are the main components/parts of the SSIS package:\nADVERTISEMENT\nControl Flow\nData Flow\nPackage Explorer\nEvent handler",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) What is defined by the term 'Data Flow' in the context of SSIS?",
        "answer": "The term data flow is nothing but a process of transferring the data from the source location to a destination. In simple words, the flow of data pumping from the corresponding source to a target destination is referred to as the 'data flow'. It is a simple mechanism in which the information is traveling from one point to another.\nThere are three components of data flow, such as Source, Transformation, and Destination. SSIS allows users to gain more control over the transformation of data from start to finish. It contains several in-built transformation components that help users clean and manipulate the data in the data pipeline. To implement a data flow task in a package, the user must first attach a data flow task to a package control flow. The data flow task is then executed within the SSIS package to create, order, and run the data flow. A separate instance of the data flow engine is created for every data flow task within the SSIS package.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "5) What is defined by the term 'Control Flow' in the context of SSIS?",
        "answer": "Control flow in SSIS is the graphical structure of elements that allows users to link and program different tasks using the logical connectors and control the elements' flow. The use of control flow in SSIS helps decide how the tasks will execute. It is necessary to include at least one control flow element in the package. In simple terms, the workflow for the SSIS package is called control flow.\nTo control the order of execution or specify the condition for executing the next consecutive task or container in a package, we can include precedence constraints to join the package's tasks and containers. The control flow connects the modular data-flows in a sequence of tasks to achieve the desired result.\nIn SSIS, there are mainly three following types of control flow elements:\nTasks that provide functionalities (such as create backups, connect to FTP, execute scripts or SQL tasks, etc.) in packages.\nContainers that provide structures (such as sequential, for loop, for each loop).\nPrecedence Constraints that join tasks, containers, and executable in a sequential control flow.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) What is meant by Data Transformation in SSIS?",
        "answer": "Data transformation is the critical SSIS process used to extract specific data from the corresponding data source. Once the extraction is completed, the process further helps to manage and transfer the extracted data to a separate file we have selected. The data transformation generally implements several rules and functionalities to the extracted data to derive the data for loading into the separate file or end file (also called end target).",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) What, according to you, are the most significant differences between SSIS and DTS?",
        "answer": "SSIS DTS\nSSIS stands for SQL Server Integration Services. DTS stands for Data Transformation Services.\nIt has powerful and complex error handling support. It has limited error handling support.\nIt contains message boxes in .NET scripts. It contains message boxes in ActiveX scripting.\nIt consists of an interactive deployment wizard. It does not have any deployment wizard.\nIt has a wide range for the number of transformations. It has a limited number of transformations.\nIt is suitable for complete BI (Business Intelligence) integration. It does not support any BI functionality.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "8) How will you differentiate SSIS from Informatica?",
        "answer": "SSIS and Informatica both perform well for the medium SQL server environment and are secure enough to use. However, there are some differences:\nSSIS Informatica\nIt is easy to use and maintain. It is easy to use but difficult to maintain as compared to SSIS.\nIt can be easily implemented. It is a bit difficult to implement.\nIt has no cost, meaning it is cost-free or free to use. It is quite expensive.\nWhen it comes to productivity, SSIS is considered a moderate option. It has comparatively higher productivity while implementing larger applications.\nSSIS is a newer approach. Informatica is older than SSIS.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) What is the meant by SSIS Catalog? Can you deploy your packages in SSIS Catalog?",
        "answer": "The SSIS Catalog is generally defined as the database that is used to store all the deployed packages. This is mainly used to increase the security of the stored packages. Besides, it is also helpful in handling and controlling the deployed packages.\nIn addition, the SSIS Catalog allows users to deploy their own packages. The packages are stored there as a centralized storage database.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) What is 'Task' in SSIS?",
        "answer": "A task is nothing but a method of a programming language used to carry out an individual component of work. In SSIS, a task is generally related to the database to achieve specific desired results.\nIn SSIS, the tasks are mainly divided into the following two categories:\nDatabase Maintenance Tasks\nControl Flow Tasks",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) Why do we use the Bulk Insert Task in SSIS?",
        "answer": "The 'bulk insert task' in SSIS is mainly used to upload vast amounts of data from flat files to SQL Server. In this process, only OLE DB connections to the destination database are supported.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) What is defined by the term 'Container' in SSIS?",
        "answer": "A container is defined as the set of tasks linked logically. In SSIS, the container's use is essential as it allows us to manage the scope of the task together.\nThere are mainly four types of containers used in SSIS:\nTask Host Container\nSequence Container\nForeach Loop Container\nFor Loop Container",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) What are the different types of containers used in SSIS?",
        "answer": "There are mainly three different types of containers used in SSIS, such as:\nSequence Container: This type of container is used to put all similar tasks in the same group. The sequence container is considered an organization container primarily used for those packages, which are more complex.\n\nFor Loop Container: This type of container is mainly used to execute any particular task to a specific number of times. The For Loop Container helps execute the same tasks several times instead of creating multiple packages or executing the entire package multiple times. For example- Assume, we want to update records for any task 10 times. We can put the task inside the 'for loop container' and assign a value 10 as the loop's end value. Doing so will execute the same task 10 times within the same package.\nFor Each Loop Container: This type of container is used in the scenario where we want to execute the task multiple times, but we are unsure how many times a task should perform. Using 'for each loop container', the task is executed any number of times until it satisfies the given condition. For example, suppose we want to delete all the files inside a folder, and we are not sure about the number of files inside the folder. Therefore, we can apply 'for each loop container' that will go through the collection of files one by one and delete them until the collection is empty.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) Define Precedence Constraint in the context of SSIS?",
        "answer": "Precedence constraints are defined as commands that instruct the system to follow the specific order to execute tasks. We can define the logical sequence of all the tasks using precedence constraints. In this case, the tasks will only be executed if they satisfy the condition or order specified in precedence constraint. These constraints instruct tasks to follow specific execution routes based on the success or failure of other existing tasks.\nThere are three main types of indication methods:\nSuccess: This is indicated by a green line in a control flow. The workflow will proceed in case the preceding container executes successfully.\nFailure: This is indicated by a red line in a control flow. The workflow will proceed in case the preceding container's execution fails.\n\nCompletion: This is indicated by a blue line in a control flow. The workflow will precede in case the preceding container's execution completes. This method is independent of success or failure status.\nApart from this, when constraints are used with logical operators, the workflow will only proceed if the constraints and expression evaluate to 'true'.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) What do you understand by the SSIS breakpoint?",
        "answer": "A breakpoint is an SSIS property that allows developers to pause the package's execution in the business intelligence system. It is generally referred to as the stopping point at any specific state within the code. The use of breakpoint is widespread as it helps to suddenly stop the execution at any desired point and enables the developers to re-review the status of variables, data or the entire package.\nSSIS breakpoints are generally configured in BIDS (Business Intelligence Development Studio). To apply or remove breakpoints, we are required to follow the below steps:\nFirst, navigate to the control flow interface within BIDS.\nRight-click on any particular object where we want to apply/remove the breakpoint.\nClick on the 'edit breakpoint' option.\nSet the breakpoint or disable it accordingly.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) What do you understand by a checkpoint in SSIS?",
        "answer": "In SSIS, a checkpoint is nothing but a saving point that helps developers to restart or load the project from any specific point. This concept is mainly used to restart the project from the point of failure instead of loading the entire project again. Suppose we are working on any file, and it suddenly crashes due to an unexpected error. If we have configured the property to 'true', the package will create a checkpoint.\nThe checkpoint generally creates a checkpoint file that contains the information about the package execution. The next time when we run the package, the package execution is restarted from the checkpoint or the point of failure. If the package executes without any error, the checkpoint and the checkpoint file are both deleted. Therefore, a checkpoint is considered as safeguards for any SSIS project, in case something goes wrong, we will have a backup.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) For which type of container, the checkpoint data is not saved?",
        "answer": "The checkpoint data is not saved for Loop containers, such as 'For Loop' and 'For Each Loop'.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) What type of variables can be created in SSIS?",
        "answer": "SSIS allows us to create two types of variables, such as global variables and task-specific variables. Global variables are the one which remains available for all tasks within the complete process. Besides, variables created in tasks are known as task-specific variables and remain available only within the task.\nBoth of these variables are almost similar to function level variables in programming.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) What is the role of connection managers in SSIS?",
        "answer": "The connection managers are mainly helpful when we want to collect data from different sources and further write it to any particular destination. The connection manager helps communicate with the system and give the desired information to the system like database name, server name, data provider information, authentication mechanism, etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) What are the types of Lookup Cache Modes present in SSIS?",
        "answer": "There are mainly three different types of Lookup Cache Modes present in SSIS Lookup Transformation:\nFull Cache Mode: This type of cache mode helps SSIS query the database before the beginning of the data-flow task execution. This mode is a critical part of the pre-execute phase. Besides, SSIS copies all the data from the reference table (or lookup table) into the SSIS lookup cache during full cache mode.\nPartial Cache Mode: This cache mode helps SSIS to query the database against new rows from different sources. In this mode, the row is cached into the SSIS lookup cache only in the case when there is a subsequent match. Once the cache gets full, SSIS automatically starts removing existing rows based on the match and usage stats. After that, new matching rows are loaded into the lookup cache.\nNo Cache Mode: As the name suggests, SSIS doesn't cache any rows in this cache mode unless there are two subsequent sources with the same lookup values. In 'No Cache Mode', the database is queried to get the match data/value from the reference table for each row coming through the source.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "21) How can you deploy SSIS packages?",
        "answer": "To deploy SSIS packages, we must first execute the Deployment Manifest File given by SSIS Project BUILD. Next, we are required to either deploy the entire package onto the SQL Server or File System. It is good to deploy packages onto SQL Server because it is much faster than deploying onto the File System.\nAnother method of deploying packages is to directly import packages from SSMS to File System or SQL Server.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) Can you log SSIS Executions?",
        "answer": "SSIS has several features, and one of them is logging. The logging allows the system to analyze and write log entries during the run-time events. Additionally, users can also add custom messages. However, this option is not enabled by default. Due to integration services, there is support for a wide variety of different sets, including various log options. The Integration Services help write log entries to different formats, such as text files, XML files, SQL Server, SQL Server Profiler, Windows Event Log, etc.\nThis means the users can log SSIS Executions. In SSIS, Logs are associated with the packages and maintained at the package level. Every task or container in a package is allowed to log information to another package log. Apart from this, we can manually enable tasks and containers in any package for logging even though the package itself is not allowed or enabled to log.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) How does an error occur in SSIS, and what are the most critical errors in SSIS?",
        "answer": "In most cases, the error occurs during transformation due to unexpected input of data values. There can be several different scenarios when an error may occur. For example- while applying a transformation to column data, loading data into destinations, extracting data from sources, etc.\nThe most critical errors commonly found in SSIS are:\nData Connection Errors: This type of error is commonly seen when the connection manager cannot be initialized with a connection string. This can be seen in both the data-source and the data-destination, along with the control flow that uses the connection strings.\nData Transformation Errors: This type of error is observed while converting the data from the data source to a destination (in the data pipeline).\nExpression Evaluation Errors: This type of error can usually be seen in a scenario where values evaluated at a run-time exhibit invalid performance.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "In SSIS, a workflow is a sequential set of instructions or commands that instruct the program executor to follow specific flow when executing tasks and containers within an SSIS package.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Data profiling is the process in which analysis is done to better understand the source data's state in terms of data cleaning, data pattern identification, numbers or nulls in data, etc. The data profiling task is generally used in the starting stages of the project development cycle to ensure that it supports destination design schema. Additionally, the process also helps figure whether the data is ready to be used and where it should be used within the current development cycle. The data profiling task doesn't help while developing standard recurring ETL packages.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "26) Why do we use the Ignore Failure option in SSIS?",
        "answer": "The ignore failure option in SSIS is mainly used to ignore the errors during the transformation process. Using this, an error is ignored, and the data row is iterated to move on to the next transformation.\nThis option helps in a scenario where we have incorrect data (JUNK data) coming from the source. We can use the Ignore failure option to redirect such data to another transformation instead of failing the entire package. The option simply allows us to move only valid data to the destination. Additionally, it helps to move incorrect data into a separate file.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "In SSIS, all the tasks and packages contain a property referred to as Logging Mode. The event logging mode properly allows or accept the following three values:\nEnabled: This option helps us to log the components.\nDisabled: This option allows us to disable the components.\nUserParentSetting: This option allows us to modify or optimize the parent's settings.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "28) How can we stop any package that is running in SSIS forever?",
        "answer": "It depends on the condition where the package is running. In case the package is running inside the SQL Agent, we can explicitly kill the entire process by implementing T-SQL. Besides, if the package is running inside the SSIS catalog, we must use the stop-operation stored method. We can either use Active Operations windows to stop the process running in the SSIS catalog.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "29) What are the main steps to be following for creating deployment utility in SSIS?",
        "answer": "Deployment is the process of changing a package state from development-mode to the executable-mode. When it comes to deploying the SSIS package, one can simply deploy it by using right-click on the Integration Services project and then clicking on 'build'. Doing this will create a file named 'package.dtsx' inside the folder named 'projectbin'.\nJust similar to this, one can also create the deployment utility. The deployment utility usually helps deploy the package at either an SQL server or as a file on any other location. To create the deployment utility, one needs to follow the steps given below:\nNavigate to the project and right-click on it.\nDouble-click on the 'properties' option.\nSelect the box next to 'True' option under createDeploymentUitlity. Here, one can also choose the location of the path for the deployment.\nSave the changes and close the window. Next, right-click on the project again and click on the build option.\nIt will create a deployment folder in the BIN folder of the main project location.\nA .manifest file will be created in the deployment folder. Next, double-click on the .manifest file and select the option to deploy the package on the SQL server.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "The following are the different types of supported file formats and connections in SSIS:\nXML\nExcel\nODBC\nOLEDB\nFlat File\n.net SQLClient",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "ssis"
    }
]